<page>
    <title>Merkury MI-WW218/pairing</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>46430</id>
    <revision>
      <id>352740</id>
      <parentid>352724</parentid>
      <timestamp>2024-03-10T21:25:28Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>DarkShadow</username>
        <id>3096572</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>add data</comment>
      <origin>352740</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="2755" sha1="ieayg3b3ntlxz6m646xokevgexai202" xml:space="preserve">{{navbar|:Merkury MI-WW218/pairing|text=Pairing info}}
=== How to Pair the Merkury Smart Plug ===
https://support.merkurysmart.com/hc/en-us/articles/15424229779099-How-to-Pair-the-Merkury-Smart-Plug

Prior to beginning the pairing process, ensure you have downloaded the Merkury Smart App and successfully created an account. If so, you are ready to start the pairing process!

What’s needed

:Know your Wi-Fi network and password
:Make sure your mobile device is running iOS® 14 or higher or Android™ 10 or higher
:Make sure you’re connecting to a 2.4GHz Wi-Fi network (Merkury Smart app cannot connect to 5GHz networks)
:Make sure that the Bluetooth is enabled on your mobile device.

Step 1   On the Home screen select the Devices button from bottom right to add your new device

[[File:Mceclip0.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 2  From the Devices screen, select the (+) icon in the top right corner

[[File:Mceclip1.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 3  Select the device to pair, then select confirm. 

Get Ready to Pair screen and ensure you select Allow/Ok for pop-up’s related to Location and  Bluetooth as these are mandatory to continue

[[File:Mceclip4.png|200px|alt text]]

[[File:Mceclip5.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 4  Power on your device, select Continue to pair if the indicator light is flashing on your

device. If the indicator light is not flashing press the power button on the side of the

device and hold in until indicator light starts flashing.

[[File:Mceclip6.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 5  Select continue on the Confirm Pairing Mode screen.

[[File:Mceclip7.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 6  Select your Wi-Fi network, enter the password and select continue

[[File:Mceclip8.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 7  iOS users will see a pop-up to join the network, select Join

[[File:Mceclip9.png|200px|alt text]]

:Android users may or may not see a pop-up to select the network that begins with

Merkury-xxxx. When you see the pop-up, tap on the Merkury device’s network

The screen will then be followed by three screens (Shown below) as the device is connecting to the network

[[File:Mceclip10.png|200px|alt text]]

[[File:Mceclip11.png|200px|alt text]]

[[File:Mceclip12.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 8   Select Continue on the Device paired screen.

[[File:Mceclip13.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 9   Name your device or select a preset name to be displayed on the Home Screen, then

:select next.

[[File:Mceclip14.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 10 Select Continue on the Congratulations! Screen.

[[File:Mceclip15.png|200px|alt text]]

Step 11 Select Okay on the Updating your device screen to return to the home screen.

[[File:Mceclip16.png|200px|alt text]]

You’re all set!  Your Merkury Smart Plug- In is now paired!

[[Category:Merkury]]</text>
      <sha1>ieayg3b3ntlxz6m646xokevgexai202</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>