<page>
    <title>Tenda AC15/Tomato</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>26848</id>
    <revision>
      <id>113028</id>
      <parentid>75971</parentid>
      <timestamp>2021-04-30T14:08:38Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Ivanp</username>
        <id>30643979</id>
      </contributor>
      <origin>113028</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="2779" sha1="eaypsx39foqccnp1asao64zjxpc0xg7" xml:space="preserve">https://www.linksysinfo.org/index.php?threads/tenda-ac15-ac1900-tomato-firmware-support.71709/post-268806

As of July 2017, the Tenda AC15 is supported by '''Fresh Tomato''' ([https://freshtomato.org/downloads/freshtomato-arm/ download available here], go to the latest year -&gt; the latest version -&gt; '''K26ARM''' -&gt; '''[[Tenda AC15]]'''). Many thanks to @kille72 and @marto12 for their hard work adding Tomato firmware support for this excellent router! There was a bug: Tomato can't seem to turn on the power amplifiers for the 5 GHz WiFi, which means that the signal strength is down -25 dB from expected (that's a measly 5.6% full power!). As of May 2020, this bug has been fixed.

To upgrade the firmware to Tomato (or restore the firmware back to Tenda OEM), you will need to use the router's CFE, because the two platforms use a different firmware format and will not accept each other's firmware files for an upgrade. Basically, you will need to:

#Connect an Ethernet cable between your PC and port 1 on the router.
#Set your PC to use a static IP address of '''192.168.0.2''' ([[TechInfoDepot:Network/How to Assign a Static IP Address|instructions are here]] if you need them).
#If the router is on, turn it off. Find the reset hole at the top of the router and insert a paperclip to hold the reset button down. While holding reset down, power the router on.
#After about 25-30 seconds, the right-most LED (with the gear/settings symbol) should turn on. If it doesn't, you probably didn't hold the reset button down the whole time; go back to step 3 and try again.
#Release the reset button and go to your PC.
#Open http://192.168.0.1/ in a web browser to pull up the CFE screen.
#Use the CFE screen to upload the desired firmware binary file (Tomato or OEM). Some browsers may timeout before the firmware is fully loaded, and you'll get an error message instead of a message saying that the router is rebooting; just go back to step 6. If it fails again, perhaps try with Internet Explorer.
#Give the router about five minutes to upload, flash and reboot. It will look like nothing is happening. When the router reboots, all the lights will flash briefly. Once Tomato is up and running, the two WiFi LEDs will light up on the front of the router.
#At this point, click the Continue link (or reopen http://192.168.0.1/ in your web browser) to configure your new firmware. Default username and password are '''root''' &amp; '''admin'''.
#As the Tenda settings are incompatible with Tomato, go to '''Administration''' -&gt; '''Configuration''' -&gt; '''Restore Default Configuration''', select '''Erase all data in NVRAM memory''' and click [OK].
#Don't forget to re-set your PC to get its IP automatically when you're done! (Undo step 2.)

&lt;noinclude&gt;[[Category:Tenda]]&lt;/noinclude&gt;</text>
      <sha1>eaypsx39foqccnp1asao64zjxpc0xg7</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>