<page>
    <title>Westell ProLine 6100 (G90-610030-06)/Bridge mode</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>1029</id>
    <revision>
      <id>218517</id>
      <parentid>4941</parentid>
      <timestamp>2022-09-29T21:45:33Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>DarkShadow</username>
        <id>3096572</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>DarkShadow moved page [[Westell 6100 (G90-610030-06)/Bridge mode]] to [[Westell ProLine 6100 (G90-610030-06)/Bridge mode]]: fixed;) again?</comment>
      <origin>4937</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="2782" sha1="g00z5r7hqwm7uidilzdnmzndx6ebkql" xml:space="preserve">First, reload the modem's settings back to factory default by depressing/letting go the Reset button on the back of the modem (see pic above).

Now, connect one computer directly to the 6100's ETHERNET Port and put the computer on the same subnet by:

 1. Rght-click on My Network Places and select Properties
   2. Right-click on your LAN connection and select Properties

[[File:Westell 6100 image001.jpg|350px|alt text]]

The following will pop-up. Go ahead and use the following values:

[[File:Westell 6100 image002.jpg|350px|alt text]]

Click on OK and OK again.

Open up a browser and go to http://192.168.1.1/

[[File:Westell 6100 image004.jpg|700px|alt text]]

The default user name is: '''admin'''

The default password is: '''password'''

Enter those and click OK.

You will then be directed to a page to assign your own Administration Name (aka user name) and password '''for the modem/router'''.

[[File:Westell 6100 image006.jpg|700px|alt text]]

Enter your new Administration Name and Password and click on ''change'' and click on OK when prompted.

You will be automatically directed to the home page of the modem/router:

[[File:Westell 6100 image008.jpg|700px|alt text]]

(You will be prompted for the NEW user name and password the very next time click on any kind of link for the modem.)

Ideally at this point, you would use the ''release'' (or &quot;disconnect&quot;) button.

If the IP release doesn't work, then go to Status and select ''About'' to get this page:

[[File:Westell 6100 image010.jpg|700px|alt text]]

Next, click on Configuration and select Private LAN Connection:

[[File:Westell 6100 image012.jpg|700px|alt text]]

You'll get the following page.

[[File:Westell 6100 image014.jpg|700px|alt text]]

Uncheck ''Private LAN DHCP Server Enable'' and the page should automatically refresh to:

[[File:Westell 6100 image016.jpg|700px|alt text]]

Click on ''save''.

Next, click on ''Configuration'' and select ''VC Configuration''

[[File:Westell 6100 image018.jpg|700px|alt text]]&lt;br&gt;
[[File:Westell 6100 image020.jpg|700px|alt text]]

Click the ''edit'' button of the &lt;font color=red&gt;'''VPI/VCI 0/35 AND MAKE SURE IT IS ENABLED!!! DISABLE every other one!'''&lt;/font&gt;

The following will pop up:

[[File:Westell 6100 image021.jpg|350px|alt text]]

Click on the ''Mode'' drop-down menu and select ''Bridge'':

[[File:Westell 6100 image022.jpg|350px|alt text]]

The pop-up will automatically refresh and should look like:

[[File:Westell 6100 image023.jpg|350px|alt text]]

Click on ''set VC'' and click ''OK'' when prompted to reset the modem. Ideally at this point, if the 6100 hasn't released the IP already it would do so at this point.

Once the modem comes back up, you're in Bridge Mode. Congratulations!

[[Category:Documentation]]
[[Category:Westell]]</text>
      <sha1>g00z5r7hqwm7uidilzdnmzndx6ebkql</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>