<page>
    <title>Linksys WRT54G v2.0</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>49037</id>
    <revision>
      <id>323832</id>
      <parentid>237904</parentid>
      <timestamp>2019-10-05T18:02:01Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>imported&gt;M86</username>
        <id>0</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>this triplet serves no use here</comment>
      <origin>323832</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="13932" sha1="41thiikwss49569j9n90iumnbkz2xea" xml:space="preserve">{{Wireless embedded system
|brand=Linksys
|model=WRT54G
|revision=v2.0
|series=WRT54G
|image1=Linksys_WRT54G-02.jpg
|image1_size=200px
|serialnum_prefix=CDF5
|fcc_date=11/24/2003
|manuf_country=China
|is_manuf=No
|manuf=CyberTAN
|availability=common
|type=wireless router
|fcc_id=Q87-WRT54GV2
|ic_id=3839A-WRT54GV2
|pwr_v=12
|pwr_amp=1
|pwr_conn=barrel
|pwr_barrel_outer=5
|pwr_barrel_inner=2.5
|pwr_barrel_len=12
|cpu1_brand=Broadcom
|cpu1_model=BCM4712
|cpu1_cspeed=200
|fla1=4
|fla1_brand=Intel
|fla1_model=TE28F320C3BD70
|ram1=16
|ram1_brand=Mira
|ram1_model=P2V64S40DTP
|ram1_num=2
|wi1_chip1_brand=Broadcom
|wi1_chip1_model=BCM4712
|wi1_chip2_brand=Broadcom
|wi1_chip2_model=BCM2050
|wi1_802dot11_protocols=bg
|wi1_ant_conn=RP-TNC
|eth_cpu=true
|sw_brand=ADMtek
|sw_model=ADM6996L
|lan_speed=100M
|lan_ports=4
|wan_speed=100M
|wan_ports=1
|stock_os=Linux
|tp_firmware=DD-WRT,OpenWrt,Tomato,Tomato (Shibby),TomatoUSB, Broadband-Hamnet
|802dot11_protocols=bg
|default_ssid=linksys
|default_ssid_regex=^linksys$
|default_ip=192.168.1.1
|default_pass=admin
|oui=00:0C:41,00:0F:66,00:12:17,00:13:10
|oui_eth=00:0C:41,00:0F:66,00:12:17,00:13:10
}}
{{TagLine|Wireless-G Broadband Router}}
:{{SupportPage|vendor=Linksys|model=WRT54G|pid=01t80000003KXPxAAO}} {{•}} [http://support.linksys.com/en-us/wireless/lbc/WRT54G/download Downloads (US)]

*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/datasheet/wrt54gv8-ds.pdf Datasheet.pdf]
*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/quickinstall/1224638367420/WRT54G-v1.1_qi.pdf Quick Install.pdf]
*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/userguide/WRT54G_UG_WEB_20070529.pdf User Guide.pdf]

Additional FCC ID of Q87-HGA7T-1 (Linksys HGA7T, high gain antennas)
:OD/ID measurements may not be exact
{{WiFiCert|W001861|12/29/2003}}
{{WDTOC|embedded}}

==Links of Interest==
*[http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linksys_WRT54G_series WRT54G series on '''Wikipedia''']
*[http://wiki.openwrt.org/oldwiki/openwrtdocs/hardware/linksys/wrt54g WRT54G page on the '''OpenWrt''' wiki]
*[http://www.dd-wrt.com/wiki/index.php/Linksys_WRT54G/GL/GS/GX Linksys WRT54Gxx page on the '''DD-WRT''' wiki]
*[http://www.dd-wrt.com/phpBB2/viewtopic.php?t=77084 WRT54G v2.0 brick just after hard reset]
*[[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/NEWD or VINT|NEWD or VINT]]
*[https://www.ifixit.com/Teardown/Linksys+WRT54G+Teardown/75660 Teardown on '''iFixit''']

==Flashing==
{{Flashnotice}}
===Flashing DD-WRT===
{{DDWRTNotice|vintstable}}
{{DDWRTNotice|k24req}}
*[[dd-wrt-wiki:Linksys WRT54G v2.0|Linksys WRT54G v2.0]]
*[http://www.dd-wrt.com/dd-wrtv2/down.php?path=downloads%2Fv24%2FBroadcom%2FBroadcom+Generic%2Fvintage/ VINTage firmware]. Details [http://www.dd-wrt.com/phpBB2/viewtopic.php?t=31978&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=0 here].

# Read the peacock announcement found here: http://www.dd-wrt.com/phpBB2/viewtopic.php?t=51486
# Do a [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/Hard reset or 30/30/30|Hard reset or 30/30/30]] on the router according to note 1 of the peacock announcement (30/30/30)
# Set a static IP on your computer to 192.168.1.7. Subnet mask should be 255.255.255.0.
# Connect the lan cable from your computer to a LAN port of your router. Make sure your router is plugged in. Nothing should be connected to your computer or the router except the lan cable between them. Turn your firewall and any wireless computer connections OFF.
# Power cycle the router (uplug the power from the router for 30 seconds and then plug it back in)
# Open your browser to 192.168.1.1 by putting that in the browser address window of your browser. You should open the linksys webgui and NOT a page that says Management Mode. If you see management mode, power cycle the router again.
# Leave the username blank and enter &quot;admin&quot; as the password
# Go to administration and firmware upgrade
# Navigate to the folder that you are using, and select [ftp://dd-wrt.com/others/eko/V24_TNG/svn15230/dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_mini.bin dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_mini.bin]
# Hit upgrade
# When you get a message that the upgrade is successful, wait FIVE FULL minutes before continuing.
# If you don't get success, repeat from steps 6 up to this one. If you still don't get success, clear your browser cache. Try using a different browser as well, to navigate to 192.168.1.1.
# When you can access the dd-wrt webgui using a browser at 192.168.1.1, power cycle the router.
# When you can again access the dd-wrt webgui using a browser at 192.168.1.1, do another [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/Hard reset or 30/30/30|Hard reset or 30/30/30]] on the router.
# At this point you can choose to put a different build on, depending on what you needs are.
# Reset your computer ethernet connection to auto IP and auto DNS
# Check for recommended builds [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT#Build_Links|here]]

===Flashing OpenWrt===
[[openwrtwiki:oldwiki/openwrtdocs/hardware/linksys/wrt54g|'''Linksys WRT54G''']]

==Reverting==
===Reverting to OEM Firmware from DD-WRT===
#Read the peacock announcement found here: http://www.dd-wrt.com/phpBB2/viewtopic.php?t=51486
#Do a [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/Hard reset or 30/30/30|Hard reset or 30/30/30]] on the router according to note 1 of the peacock announcement (30/30/30)
#Set a static IP on your computer to 192.168.1.7. Subnet mask should be 255.255.255.0.
#Connect the lan cable from your computer to a LAN port of your router. Make sure your router is plugged in. Nothing should be connected to your computer or the router except the lan cable between them. Turn your firewall and any wireless computer connections OFF.
#Power cycle the router (uplug the power from the router for 30 seconds and then plug it back in)
#Open your browser to 192.168.1.1 by putting that in the browser address window of your browser. You should open the linksys webgui and NOT a page that says Management Mode. If you see management mode, power cycle the router again.
#Enter your username and password
#Go to administration and firmware upgrade
#Navigate to the folder that you are using, and select [http://homedownloads.cisco.com/downloads/firmware/1224639846883/WRT54G_v4.21.1_fw.zip WRT54G_v4.21.1_fw.zip] once you've unzipped it.
#Hit upgrade
#When you get a success, wait FIVE FULL minutes.
#When you can again access the Linksys webgui using a browser at 192.168.1.1, do another [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/Hard reset or 30/30/30|Hard reset or 30/30/30]] on the router.
#Reset your computer ethernet connection to auto IP and auto DNS

===Serial===
====Serial Pinouts====
&lt;pre&gt;
 JP1
 Pin1 VCC      Pin2  VCC
 Pin3 ttyS1 TX Pin4  ttyS0 TX
 Pin5 ttyS1 RX Pin6  ttyS0 RX
 Pin7 N/C      Pin8  N/C
 Pin9 GND      Pin10 GND
&lt;/pre&gt;
{{Serial TTL Setup WinXP
|serialport       = 
|serial_port_num  = 
|serial_speed     = 
|serial_data_bits = 
|serial_parity    = 
|serial_stop_bits = 
|serial_flow_cntl = 
}}

==Pictures==
&lt;center&gt;'''DarkShadow's Unit'''
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Linksys WRT54G-02.jpg|
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v2.0b.jpg|
&lt;/gallery&gt;&lt;/center&gt;[[Has images::retail| ]]
&lt;center&gt;'''WikiDevi Images'''
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v2_board_top_rfshieldremoved.jpg|board top
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v2_board_bot.jpg|board bottom
&lt;/gallery&gt;&lt;/center&gt;[[Has images::internal| ]]
{{FCCID Q87-WRT54GV2}}

==Notes==
&lt;!-- Firmware Specific Notes Here, Device Specific Above --&gt;
===Various additional info===
===wl -i eth1 revinfo===
&lt;pre&gt;
vendorid 0x14e4
deviceid 0x4329
radiorev 0x92056000
chipnum 0xb83a
chiprev 0x0
corerev 0x11
boardid 0x4fb
boardvendor 0x14e4
boardrev P201
driverrev 0x50a9300
ucoderev 0x1fc009d
bus 0x0
phytype 0x4
phyrev 0x6
anarev 0x8
&lt;/pre&gt;

===DD-WRT Notes===
Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Bualdoot|Bualdoot]] on 12-Dec-2008: The comments below are from before I added the install instructions above. The comment below was referring to a comment that i removed, because it talked about not being sure if the WRT54Gv2 had more than 2MB memory, which of course we know it does. As for the instructions it gave that he refers to, they were not very clear, so, I made my own set of instructions based off the v1-v1.1 instructions.

all set [Comment from jas3 on 16-Mar-2008: The above worked for me. I then updated from standard to dd-wrt.v23_vpn_generic.bin which succeeded as well] 
May08, When upgrading to v24, please do a full firmware reset (hold reset button for 30 seconds on power up). I did not do this when upgrading to v24 and was getting all sorts of strange behaviors from my router. After resetting and then reconfiguring the router, all was well.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:MoT|MoT]] 11:01, 2 Jul 2007 (CEST) : I have been able to flash the VPN version on my V2.0, after flashing from the original Linksys firmware to the mini version first. I followed the V4 tutorial.&lt;br&gt;
After flashing to the mini version, I couldn't flash to the VPN version at first, as I was immediately redirected to a blank page when trying to flash. This seemed to be a problem with IE7, with Firefox, it went fine.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:I Use Dial|I Use Dial]] 13:54, 21 Jul 2007 (PDT) I installed mini to my v2.2 through Linksys GUI and had forgotten to reset factory defaults before uploading. I had same problem with blank screen loading but Firefox didn't help. Unplugged it, did a hard reset, unplugged it again, and everything was fine. Then uploaded latest stable version without issue.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Glc|Glc]] 19:00, 31 October 2007 (CET) v2.0 Installed mini generic over Linksys firmware using the web interface, followed by standard generic with web interface. Setting to PPPoE knocked out the WAN port, worked fine in DHCP. Flashed back to mini generic and everything works as advertised.

Comment : Installed mini, then standard generic. No problems except I can't overclock. I try 216 but when applying and restarting all router lights flash together periodically every few seconds. Hard resetting using button takes router back to factory settings and then it works fine. Tried twice on v23 sp2 and once on v24 RC5.

Comment (March 19, 2008) : Just installed dd-wrt on my WRT54G v2 router. I started by installing wrt54gv2 v24 rc6.2 mini through the Linksys web interface and then after I got that installed I used the new dd-wrt mini interface to install wrt54gv2 v24rc6.2 standard generic. Everything is running smoothly and I had no problems in getting dd-wrt installed.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Doppelbock|Doppelbock]] 22:15, 18 April 2008 (PDT) I just installed v23 SP2 full version (generic) on a WRT54G v2.2 that I bought used on eBay and don't seem to have any issues. I had to do a 30-second reset to log into the dd-wrt gui in IE but other than that it's been smooth sailing so far.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Djmoore|Djmoore]] 11:02, 21 June 2008 (CEST) Installed v24-9517_VINT_mini on WRT54G 2.2 using Firefox 3 running on Linux/Ubuntu 8.04 with no problems. 30-30-30 reset before and after.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Erocku|Erocku]] June 2008: I was able to install the v24-9517_VINT_mini on my WRT54G v2.0. After the install I was then able to install the v24-9517_VINT_std with no problems. I was even able to do it from Safari.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:jcp rev|jcp_rev]] August 2008: I Installed two days ago dd-wrt.v24_vpn_generic.bin on my WRT54G v2.0. previous version dd-wrt.v23_mini_generic.bin. I did it from Firefox 3. using the standard procedure.

Comment --[[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Dlfretz|Dlfretz]] 18:05, 08/29/2008 (CEST) I was able to install the standard version after flashing the mini version. I just couldn't go straight to the standard version. I installed with Firefox 3.0 on Windows. This is an original Linksys WRT-54G version 2.0

Comment: 28 Sept 08 Uploaded v24sp1-micro generic on a v.2.0 - now I can't upload anything else. Have tried the VINt and the mega-generic and while the upload and reboot appear to be successful, the router still reports the micro version and features are unchanged.

Comment - [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:skaterkfbs|skaterkfbs]] - Followed these instructions for a v2.2 and worked perfectly. I had trouble trying to go directly from LinkSys v4.21.1 firmware to DD-WRT v24 VINT Standard. Had to use the middle DD-WRT v24 VINT Mini.

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:paillassou|paillassou]] April 2009: My WRT54Gv2.0 [serial#CDF5*****] had an old (but fun too) FIRMWARE [FW = &quot;v4.71.1 Hyperwrt 2.1b1 + Thibor15c&quot;]. I would change for DD-WRT fw. So, after a hard reset 30/30/30 on the thibor15c's fw, i was able to flash successfully, the &quot;mini version&quot; DD-WRT fw through the WEB interface of the thibor15c's fw. I was able to install, 1st, the v24-9517_VINT_mini on my WRT54G v2.0. Reboot OK - DDWRTmini works fine =&gt; hard reset 30/30/30. After that, I was then able to install the v24-9517_VINT_std with no problems. Reboot OK - DDWRTstd works fine =&gt; hard reset 30/30/30. I was even able to do it from IE7. Install = FREEBOXv4 + WRT54Gv2.0 with FW=DD-WRTv24-9517_VINT_std. All is right. Thanks a lot for the tutorial and informations ;o)

Comment [[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Atlasit|atlasit]] July 2009: After installing the mini firmware to a WRT54G v2.0 using IE8, clicked the Continue button and did a hard reset. The screen that comes up after the reset prompts to change the user and password of the router. It would not continue after clicking the button until I viewed the page in 'Compatibility Mode'. Then it took the changes.

Comment --[[dd-wrt-wiki:User:Educmale|Educmale]] 06:07, 11 November 2009 (CET): With Ver2.2, I noticed that both the VINT-std and the STD versions install and work fine, almost ---- the STD version won't allow a virtual wireless LAN to connect using WPA2-pers security, while operating in repeater mode. It acts like there is a bug there, in the STD version, in that virtual area—Odd, as the STD version -will- connect as a wireless access point, using the same WPA2-pers setup. In contrast, VINT will allow the same set up to let the WPA2-pers function either as an AP or a virtual wireless Lan. [The STD version was the one available 3days ago; perhaps this bug will be fixed, one day?]</text>
      <sha1>41thiikwss49569j9n90iumnbkz2xea</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>