<page>
    <title>Linksys WRT54G v1.0</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>50915</id>
    <revision>
      <id>255297</id>
      <parentid>255296</parentid>
      <timestamp>2019-07-05T05:04:09Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>imported&gt;M86</username>
        <id>0</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Text replacement - &quot;speed=10/100&quot; to &quot;speed=100M&quot;</comment>
      <origin>255297</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="7888" sha1="6ialnoqv01xbnzz6eu2fg3adkcby20l" xml:space="preserve">{{Wireless embedded system
|brand=Linksys
|model=WRT54G
|revision=v1.0
|series=WRT54G
|image1=Linksys_WRT54G-02.jpg
|image1_size=200px
|serialnum_prefix=CDF0 or CDF1
|fcc_date=12/23/2002
|is_manuf=No
|manuf=BroMax
|type=wireless router
|fcc_id=PKW-WM54G,O6M-WM606
|pwr_v=5
|pwr_amp=2
|pwr_conn=barrel
|cpu1_brand=Broadcom
|cpu1_model=BCM4702
|cpu1_cspeed=125
|fla1=4
|ram1=16
|expansion_if_types=Mini PCI
|expansion_minipci_num=1
|wi1_module=BroMax WM606-BF
|wi1_module_if=Mini PCI
|wi1_chip1_brand=Broadcom
|wi1_chip1_model=BCM4306
|wi1_chip2_brand=Broadcom
|wi1_chip2_model=BCM2050
|wi1_802dot11_protocols=bg
|wi1_ant_conn=U.FL,RP-TNC
|eth_cpu=true
|sw_brand=ADMtek
|sw_model=ADM6996
|lan_speed=100M
|lan_ports=4
|wan_speed=100M
|wan_ports=1
|stock_os=Linux
|tp_firmware=DD-WRT,OpenWrt,Tomato,TomatoUSB, Broadband-Hamnet
|802dot11_protocols=bg
|default_ssid=linksys
|default_ssid_regex=^linksys$
|default_ip=192.168.1.1
|default_pass=admin
}}
{{TagLine|Wireless-G Broadband Router}}
:{{SupportPage|vendor=Linksys|model=WRT54G|pid=01t80000003KXPxAAO}} {{•}} [http://support.linksys.com/en-us/wireless/lbc/WRT54G/download Downloads (US)]

*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/datasheet/wrt54gv8-ds.pdf Datasheet.pdf]
*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/quickinstall/1224638367420/WRT54G-v1.1_qi.pdf Quick Install.pdf]
*[http://downloads.linksys.com/downloads/userguide/WRT54G_UG_WEB_20070529.pdf User Guide.pdf]

*The FCC ID printed on the label is PKW-WM54G. 
:O6M-WM606 is, however, the FCC ID of the [[BroMax]] wireless module.
:Appears to be identical to the [[CyberTAN WG414]]
{{see also|Linksys WRT54G series}}

{{WiFiCert|W001002|06/18/2003}}
{{WDTOC|embedded}}

==Links of Interest==
*[http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linksys_WRT54G_series WRT54G series on '''Wikipedia''']
*[http://wiki.openwrt.org/oldwiki/openwrtdocs/hardware/linksys/wrt54g WRT54G page on the '''OpenWrt''' wiki]
*[http://www.dd-wrt.com/wiki/index.php/Linksys_WRT54G/GL/GS/GX Linksys WRT54Gxx page on the '''DD-WRT''' wiki]
*[[WikiDevi:DD-WRT/NEWD or VINT|NEWD or VINT]]

==Flashing==
{{Flashnotice}}
===Flashing DD-WRT===
{{DDWRTNotice|vintreq}}
{{DDWRTNotice|k24req}}
*[[dd-wrt-wiki:Linksys WRT54G v1.0 &amp; 1.1|Linksys WRT54G v1.0]]
*[http://www.dd-wrt.com/dd-wrtv2/down.php?path=downloads%2Fv24%2FBroadcom%2FBroadcom+Generic%2Fvintage/ VINTage firmware]. Details [http://www.dd-wrt.com/phpBB2/viewtopic.php?t=31978&amp;postdays=0&amp;postorder=asc&amp;start=0 here].

[[File:Fixme.gif]] This section is outdated and needs to be brought up to date!

&lt;div style='color:red; font-weight:bold'&gt;'''WARNING!!!'''&lt;br&gt;Do not use V24 RC6.X builds on the WRT v1.X units. &lt;br&gt;There is high probability that you will brick your V1.x unit by installing it..&lt;br&gt;As of 07/20/2010 v24-sp2 is unconfirmed on this device&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style='color:red; font-weight:bold'&gt;'''WARNING!!!'''&lt;br&gt;DO NOT run NEWD on WRT54G v1.0 routers! Only install VINT builds. &lt;br&gt;If you flash a NEWD build onto a v1.0 you will brick the router.&lt;/div&gt;

{{SCollapse|Upgrade
|[Comment --[[dd-wrt-wiki:User:n8hfi|n8hfi]]: On a ''very'' old WRT54G v1.0, I found it necessary to upgrade with a newer Linksys firmware before I could load DD-WRT. The original firmware (Linksys v1.00.8 Dec 24 2002) gave a 'incorrect image file' error on on both the mini and standard DD-WRT v23 SP2 images. The sequence that worked was (all done with the web GUI and-ugh-IE):
# Restore factory defaults with the original firmware.
# Upgrade to Linksys firmware version 4.21.1. You can get it [http://www.linksys.com/servlet/Satellite?c-L_CASupport_C2&amp;childpagename-US%2FLayout&amp;cid-1166859837401&amp;packedargs-sku%3DWRT54G&amp;pagename-Linksys%2FCommon%2FVisitorWrapper&amp;lid-3740137401B01&amp;displaypage-download#versiondetail here]. Read the fine print carefully, not all firmware versions work with all hardware versions.
# Then upgrade to [ftp://dd-wrt.com/others/eko/V24_TNG/svn15230/dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_mini.bin dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_mini.bin]. I got the ''Continue'' page, but never got the DD-WRT GUI.
# Hold the reset button for 30 seconds (I didn't cycle power or anything else on the router.)
# Then I got the DD_WRT GUI. I reset it to factory defaults with the GUI, although this step may have been unnecessary, since I'd just flashed it.
# Then I upgraded to [ftp://dd-wrt.com/others/eko/V24_TNG/svn15230/dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_std.bin dd-wrt.v24-15230_VINT_std.bin]. I selected the 'restore factory defaults after flashing' option while doing this.
# all set [Comment from jas3 on 16-Mar-2008: The above worked for me. I then updated from standard to dd-wrt.v23_vpn_generic.bin which succeeded as well]
# May08, When upgrading to v24, please do a full firmware reset (hold reset button for 30 seconds on power up). I did not do this when upgrading to v24 and was getting all sorts of strange behaviors from my router. After resetting and then reconfiguring the router, all was well.
#Check for recommended builds [[WikiDevi:DD-WRT#Build_Links|here]].}}

===Flashing OpenWrt===
*[[openwrtwiki:toh/linksys/wrt54g|Linksys WRT54G]]

==Pictures==
&lt;center&gt;'''Images'''
&lt;gallery&gt;
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v1.0b.jpg|
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v1.0c.jpg|
File:Linksys_WRT54G_v1.0d.jpg|
&lt;/gallery&gt;&lt;/center&gt;[[Has images::retail| ]][[Has images::internal| ]]

{{FCCID O6M-WM606}}
{{FCCID PKW-WM54G}}

==Notes==
&lt;!-- Firmware Specific Notes Here, Device Specific Above --&gt;
===DD-WRT Notes===
{{SCollapse|Notes
|[dgb: 2009.04.25 V1.0 hardware with 1.02.1 firmware]
On a V1.0 box with firmware 1.02.1 Feb 2003... First there is no administration tab, look under &quot;system&quot;. With IE and eventually with Firefox pushing the Upgrade button resulted in a chooser (browser). I choose the dd-wrt bin file and pushed the Upgrade button, the browsers each failed. IE reported the server was busy or not available. Firefox sent a dump off to Microsoft. So I located and tried to install a newer Linksys firmware load - same results. I then loaded up Netscape, turned off the blockers, configured it to open pop-ups in a new tab, choose the newer Linksys firmware and pressed update. It showed a progress bar as the firmware was loaded into the vintage box, Eventually the page went blank on '''&quot;&lt;nowiki&gt;http://192.168.1.1/upgrade.cgi&lt;/nowiki&gt;&quot;'''. Lights occasionally flicker as I impatiently wait and document the differences I've seen to this point.

I now have Linksys FW revision v4.21.1 ''and'' an Administration tab...30/30/30

Still using NS and under Administration/Firmware Upgrade I selected the dd-wrt load dd-wrt.v24-9517_vint_voip, an upload progress bar displayed followed by &quot;upgrade are failed!&quot;, I choose continue... Repeating the process has the same result. Third attempt, this time with IE - same result. I surmise that the router is not actually attempting to flash itself, but failing the .bin file. This for two reasons, the progress bar never gets much past 50% and the router never 'goes away&quot;, in fact it reports and error and wants to continue. The progress bar actually completes once then starts again before the failure notice.

Now I'm guessing here, but maybe some sick firmware developer who wasn't even in college when v1.0 hardware was available coded in an assert that the .bin file must be able to fit within the smaller modern architectures. I used IE to get the Linksys firmware to use dd-wrt.v24-9517_VINT_mini and &quot;Upgrade is successful&quot; from the unit. Pressed &quot;continue&quot; presented root/admin and here's my old friend dd-wrt! I can feel a new wireless bridge being born... 30/30/30 more Scotch, more beer.

Still using IE and using the dd-wrt upgraded to the desired ...voip load I wanted all a long. 30/30/30...

The old box is now running dd-wrt v24(05/20/08)voip uptime 1 min. There probably isn't a lot of this old stuff out there so maybe this isn't of interest to anyone else - but if you're trying, get Netscape for that first giant step...
[end dgb]}}

__NOTOC__</text>
      <sha1>6ialnoqv01xbnzz6eu2fg3adkcby20l</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>