<page>
    <title>Motorola CyberSURFR</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>53982</id>
    <revision>
      <id>275385</id>
      <parentid>275384</parentid>
      <timestamp>2019-07-05T05:52:54Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>imported&gt;M86</username>
        <id>0</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Text replacement - &quot;speed=10
|&quot; to &quot;speed=10M
|&quot;</comment>
      <origin>275385</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="3989" sha1="0uwilrvqgzkrmlbkv5fx2hwmej9afol" xml:space="preserve">{{Wired embedded system
|brand=Motorola
|model=CyberSURFR
|revision=
|upc=
|ean=
|asin=
|price=
|est_release_date=12/1996
|fcc_date=
|manuf_country=
|is_manuf=No
|manuf=
|manuf_model=
|manuf_rev=
|availability=
|type=cable modem
|fcc_id=
|ic_id=
|us_id=
|pwr_v=
|pwr_amp=
|pwr_conn=DIN (5-pin)
|cpu1_brand=Motorola
|cpu1_model=
|cpu1_cspeed=
|fla1=
|fla1_brand=
|fla1_model=
|ram1=
|ram1_brand=
|ram1_model=
|expansion_if_types=Type F (female), DB-9 (male)
|expansion_pcmcia_num=
|expansion_expresscard_num=
|expansion_minipci_num=
|expansion_minipcie_num=
|expansion_usb_num=
|jtag=
|serial=
|eth_none=
|eth_cpu=true
|sw_cpu=
|sw_brand=
|sw_model=
|lan_speed=10M
|lan_ports=1
|wan_ports=
|addl_chips=
|flags=pre-DOCSIS, CDLP, metal box
|stock_os=
|tp_firmware=
|default_ip=
|default_user=
|default_pass=
|oui_eth=
}}
{{TagLine|Motorola CyberSURFR Cable Modem}}
:[http://www.mot.com/MIMS/Multimedia/prod/specs/modemSpec.html Specifications page]

This is a non-DOCSIS cable modem. 
:Specifically, it uses '''Motorola''''s proprietary CDLP system.
:See {{WPLink|Cable modem#CDLP}} for a bit more info.

Early '''@Home Network''' installations may have been the principal 
:users of these modems.. though some post '''@Home''' networks 
:may have kept the legacy network going for a bit longer.

*[http://www.wap.org/journal/speed/needforspeed.html On '''wap.org'''] ([http://www.wap.org/journal/speed/motorolafront.jpg front], [http://www.wap.org/journal/speed/motorolaback.jpg back] images)&lt;small&gt;
:The front of the Motorola CyberSURFR has a curved face plate and six small lights. 
:The Comcast@Home logo is a stick-on label on the otherwise gray metal case.
:Instead of two RJ-11 telephone jacks on the back, it has a &quot;cable TV&quot; connector 
:(female Type F connector), an RJ-45 10BASE-T Ethernet port, an odd 9-pin D-shell 
:(DB 9-pin male) connector for &quot;testing,&quot; and a tiny reset button.&lt;/small&gt;

&lt;!-- Next, we connected the cable modem, a Motorola CyberSURFR. The CyberSURFR is a metal box about the size of a US Robotics Courier modem. Instead of two RJ-11 telephone jacks on the back, it has a &quot;cable TV&quot; connector (female Type F connector), an RJ-45 10BASE-T Ethernet port, an odd 9-pin connector for &quot;testing,&quot; and a tiny reset button. There is no ON-OFF switch, so once we plugged in the power supply, it was on. Neither technician had ever used the &quot;test&quot; port, or seen anyone else use the &quot;test&quot; port, or had any idea what you could possibly plug into it.

The front of the Motorola CyberSURFR has a curved face plate and six small lights. The Comcast@Home logo is a stick-on label on the otherwise gray metal case.

After a few minutes spent watching the lights on the front of the CyberSURFR, the cable installer announced &quot;it isn't working.&quot; The &quot;installation specialist&quot; agreed. The cable installer disappeared to check the outside connections, and the &quot;installation specialist&quot; checked the TCP/IP settings. They then compared notes, and decided to try a different CyberSURFR modem.

After a minute or so, they both agreed: &quot;this one is working fine.&quot; A quick trip to the Washington Apple Pi Web site (http://www.wap.org) confirmed that all was well.

A month later, still without ever having contacted anyone at Comcast, VISA billed $41.95 for a month of service. The entire experience was a stellar example of the wonders of downsizing: sales, installation and billing were all done by subcontractors. Based on prior failed attempts to contact some human at Comcast's cable TV service number, we have no evidence -- none -- that anyone works at Comcast.

From left to right, the connectors are for the TV cable, the power supply, the reset button (tiny hole right of the round power supply), test (small 9-pin D-shell connection), and an RJ-45 10BASE-T Ethernet port. There is no ON-OFF switch, or any configuration switches.--&gt;
*[https://archive.org/stream/Hacking_The_Cable_Modem_2006/Hacking_The_Cable_Modem_2006_djvu.txt ''Hacking The Cable Modem''] (''archive.org'')</text>
      <sha1>0uwilrvqgzkrmlbkv5fx2hwmej9afol</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>