<page>
    <title>Siemens SpeedStream 4200</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>69749</id>
    <revision>
      <id>348842</id>
      <parentid>348841</parentid>
      <timestamp>2019-07-05T05:13:14Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>imported&gt;M86</username>
        <id>0</id>
      </contributor>
      <minor/>
      <comment>Text replacement - &quot;speed=10/100&quot; to &quot;speed=100M&quot;</comment>
      <origin>348842</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="5075" sha1="d451f2kc6kgadapofqobwidqagrd48s" xml:space="preserve">{{Wired embedded system
|brand=Siemens
|model=SpeedStream
|revision=4200
|est_release_date=03/01/2004
|manuf_country=China
|is_manuf=No
|type=dsl modem
|pwr_v=12
|pwr_amp=0.5
|pwr_conn=barrel
|cpu1_brand=Texas Instruments
|cpu1_model=TNETD7300A
|cpu1_cspeed=160
|fla1=2 MiB
|fla1_brand=Macronix
|fla1_model=MX29LV160
|ram1=16 MiB
|ram1_brand=Samsung
|ram1_model=K4S281632F-TC60
|expansion_if_types=USB 1.1
|expansion_usb_num=1
|eth_cpu=true
|lan_speed=100M
|lan_ports=1
|flags=ADSL2+
|stock_boot=
|stock_os=
|tp_firmware=
|default_ip=192.168.254.254
|default_user=admin
|default_pass=
|oui_eth=
}}
{{TagLine|Ethernet ADSL Modem}}
{{see also|Siemens SpeedStream 6520}}
*[https://www.speedguide.net/routers/siemens-speedstream-4200-adsl122-router-319 On '''SpeedGuide''']
*[http://forums.whirlpool.net.au/forum-replies.cfm?t=926694 On '''WhirlPool''' forums] ([http://bc.whirlpool.net.au/bc/hardware/?action=h_view&amp;model_id=278 Spec.])
{{SCollapse|Instructions on how to bridge a SpeedStream 4200
|
As we seem to get asked a lot for instructions on how to bridge a SpeedStream 4200, and test 
:if it bridged correctly i have copied info from the Siemens site to make it easy to find

plz note instructions are for use with ethernet and not usb, 
:i suggest you only use ethernet with the 4200

Instructions for making the necessary changes are set out below:

'''SpeedStream 4200 to Bridge Mode'''

4200 Modem set-up:

* Reset the modem to ensure it is in default mode (refer instructions below).
* Type the modem's URL into the internet browser (address bar in Internet Explorer)
:Note: You need to determine the DHCP server address for the modem. 
:For Windows 2000 or XP, this can be performed by selecting “Run” from the “Start” menu:
:• type cmd, then enter
:• at the DOS prompt, type: ipconfig /all, then enter
:• note the DHCP server address. This is the modem address.
* Click &quot;Login&quot; option. The &quot;Username&quot; is admin and the &quot;Password&quot; is admin. Then click &quot;OK&quot;.
* Click the &quot;Setup&quot; option and then click the &quot;WAN interface&quot; option.
* If asked for a Username/Password use admin/admin
* Click under VC heading the &quot;8/35&quot; option.
* Click &quot;Next&gt;&gt;&quot;
* The PPPoE option should be selected and then click &quot;Next&gt;&gt;&quot; again.
* Under the heading &quot;PPPoE Type&quot; select the &quot;Bridge only&quot; option and then click &quot;Next&gt;&gt;&quot;.
* Click &quot;Finish&quot;
* A reboot is required before the new configuration takes effect. Click the word &quot;reboot&quot;. 
:An additional &quot;Reboot&quot; button will be displayed. Click this &quot;Reboot&quot; button&quot;

'''Resetting 4200 to Factory Defaults'''

Resetting the modem may be required if you have changed the modem’s settings 
:and wish to reset it to the factory default configuration.
Note: Resetting the modem will wipe all previous configurations and you will 
:need to re-enter your provider account details.

4200 Modem

*1. Using the tip of a ballpoint pen or unfolded paperclip, press and hold the Reset button located 
:on the bottom of the router. The pwr LED will blink red once, indicating that the reset has begun.
*2. Continue depressing the Reset button for four seconds or until the pwr LED begins to blink 
:alternating red-to-green.
*3. Release the Reset button.

Generic 4200 firmware: http://www.modemsupport.com.au/ (see left hand menu)

4200 user manual: http://www.modemsupport.com.au/

----

*To test the 4200 is actually running in bridge mode
connect a computer directly to the 4200 with an ethernet cable

you will need to run a windows ppp session , you can delete the ppp session 
:once you have confirmed it works correctly
PC setup for running PPPoE (for Windows):

* Go to the Control Panel from the Start Menu
* Click Network Connections
* Under the Wizard heading – click “New Connection Wizard”
* At the Network Connection Type screen, click “Connect to the Internet”
* Select “Setup my connection manually”
* Select “ Connect using a broadband connection that requires a user name and password”
* @ the Connection Name Screen, type in myisp where it asks for the ISP name
* @ the Connection Availability screen select “Anyones Use”
* @ Internet Account Information screen, enter your user name and details and ensure both 
:of the check boxes, are ticked ie for “use this account name and password when anyone anyone 
:connects to the internet from this computer”, and “make this the default internet connection”.
* Completion of New Connection Wizard, tick “add a shortcut to this connection to my desktop”.

To go online, every time you wish to connect, double click the myisp icon, enter 
:your user name and password and click “connect”.
once you confirm the above works you must remove this test setup from your computer, 
:to do this go to start / settings / control panel
select internet options / select the connections tab --- click on &quot;myisp&quot; and select 
:remove , this resets your computer back to normal.

If the above allows you to connect directly to the net then you are in bridge mode 
:and ready to connect a router or wireless router to the 4200
}}

[[Category:Documentation]]</text>
      <sha1>d451f2kc6kgadapofqobwidqagrd48s</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>