<page>
    <title>Westell ProLine 6100 (G90-610030-06)</title>
    <ns>0</ns>
    <id>68666</id>
    <revision>
      <id>379694</id>
      <parentid>379671</parentid>
      <timestamp>2022-10-03T18:00:26Z</timestamp>
      <contributor>
        <username>Omega</username>
        <id>24</id>
      </contributor>
      <comment>add links ;</comment>
      <origin>379694</origin>
      <model>wikitext</model>
      <format>text/x-wiki</format>
      <text bytes="4158" sha1="p1zlxayy4dj5iymw75djrjmz5ng7tpn" xml:space="preserve">{{Wired embedded system
|brand=Westell
|model=ProLine 6100
|revision=(G90-610030-06)
|asin=B0037BUV7Q, B000QPPY0A
|is_manuf=No
|manuf=
|type=dsl modem
|pwr_v=12
|pwr_amp=1
|pwr_conn=barrel
|cpu1_brand=Texas Instruments
|cpu1_model=
|cpu1_cspeed=
|fla1=4
|fla1_brand=
|fla1_model=
|ram1=32
|ram1_brand=
|ram1_model=
|expansion_if_types=USB 2.0
|expansion_usb_num=1
|serial=
|jtag=
|eth_cpu=true
|lan_speed=100M
|lan_ports=1
|flags=ADSL2+
|tp_firmware=
|default_ip=192.168.1.1
|default_user=
|default_pass=
|oui_eth=
}}
{{TagLine|Westell Wind River DSL Modem}}

===Introduction===
Info from [http://www.flex.com/ FlexNet] - But the original page is long gone.

{{SCollapse2|Westell 6100 ADSL Modem
|Don't mess around with the modem UNLESS, upon connecting 
:the Westell 6100 ADSL Modem to your phone line:

 You have THREE SOLID GREEN LEDs LIT (See below) and
 Your connection doesn't come up and
 You DID NOT Get your WESTELL Modem from HiTel via a 
   Flexnet Order On Your Behalf!!

If this happens to you, then maybe, just MAYBE your adsl modem isn't in BRIDGE Mode.
:If so, then these are the instructions to place it in BRIDGE mode. 
:But, don't do this unless you have to!

;UPDATE 6 April 2007:
HiTel (Hawaiian Telecom) informs me that all Westell 6100s ordered 
:thru ISPs are in a &quot;dummy modem&quot; (bridge-bridge) state permanently. 
Also, according to &quot;Guy&quot; you can NOT log into the HiTel purchased 
:Westell 6100 ADSL Modem via web browser.

:In other words, none of the following instructions will work!!! 
HiTel specs their modems from Westell to be dumbed down—the router functions 
:are disabled, the DHCP Server functions are disabled, no more management.
:..and I DO agree with this! Why create more of a hassle?

Well, you used to be able to login and look at the phone line 
:quality and stuffs like that, but who really cares, eh?
:So the HiTel Westell 6100 is already in a bridged state.

ALL YOU CAN DO IS RESET THE MODEM, which you should if there is a problem. 

To do this, leave everything powered up, and then depress the Reset Button 
:until the Power led turns AMBER, then let it go. 
Presto. RESET. Dats all you can muck up. Thank God.

;So you bought your Westell 6100 modem off Ebay?
:Okay, these instructions are for you! 
This HOW-TO is gathered (aka stolen) from various sources on the internet.
:So I don't take 100% credit for it all. But what the hay..? 
Now, a look at this puppy… }}
*'''Power''' = When lit, this light indicates there's power to the router. It should be solid green.
*'''DSL''' = When lit, this light indicates the modem is speaking to the central office (phone company).
:When working, the light should be solid green.
*'''Ethernet''' = When lit, this light indicates that the modem is communicating with your computer.
:This will be on only if you're using the Ethernet cable to connect the modem to your computer.
*'''USB''' = When lit, this light indicates that the modem is communicating with your computer.
:This will be on only if you're using the USB cable to connect the modem to your computer.
:We recommend using the Ethernet cable.
*'''DSL Line''' = Plug the phone line into this socket.
*'''Ethernet''' = What else? Plug your ethernet cable here directly from your computer!

===Westell 6100 Setup for Bridge mode===
{{SCollapse2|Westell 6100 Setup for Bridge mode|{{:Westell ProLine 6100 (G90-610030-06)/Bridge mode}}}}
===See also===
:;[https://www.dslreports.com/forum/westell Westell] • [https://www.dslreports.com/faq/6096 AT&amp;T (BellSouth)]
*[[Westell WireSpeed 2100 (A90-210030-04)]] • ADSL Modem
*[[Westell WireSpeed 2200 (B90-220030-04)]] • ADSL Modem
*[[Westell WireSpeed 2410]] (B90-241030-04) • ADSL Modem
*[[Westell WireSpeed 6100 (C90-610030-06)]] (B90-) • [https://www.dslreports.com/hardware/Westell-6100-h4133 ADSL2+] Modem ([[TI]])
*[[Westell ProLine 6100 (G90-610030-06)]] • ADSL2+ Modem

==Images==
[[File:Westell 6100 front.png|300px|WESTELL ADSL MODEM MODEL 6100]] 
[[File:Westell 6100 back.png|300px|My, my! Isn't she a cutie pie?]] 
https://i.dslr.net/syms/38c35f104c6298bda6e3a1225d0aac5e.jpg

__NOTOC__

[[Category:Documentation]]
[[Category:Westell]]</text>
      <sha1>p1zlxayy4dj5iymw75djrjmz5ng7tpn</sha1>
    </revision>
  </page>